So, Ukraine had to look at the board and
ask a simple question. What do we need
to do if we want to break [music]
Russia? Deprive it of means to wage war.
Fine. And what keeps the Russian state
functioning? Hydrocarbon exports, gas,
[music] and above all, oil. According to
the most comprehensive analysis, the
sector may account for as much as 60% of
Russia's federal budget.
So, what can we actually do? The easiest
answer would be sanctions. Ukraine will
keep lobbying for them to be tightened,
but in reality, it has limited control
over that process.
>> [music]
>> So, what should we do?
Burn the refineries.
This is, of course, an imagined
dialogue, but it captures the logic of
Ukrainian decision-makers. Ukraine
correctly identified the Russian
Federation's center of gravity
and decided to strike at that vulnerable
point. It was a far more complex project
than it may [music] sound. First came
the strategy, moving from concept to
feasibility. Then came design, logistic
chains, and finally mass production of
short, medium, and long-range drones. It
took years, but eventually Kyiv reached
full operational capability.